### **SUMMARY**

I am a Full-stack Software Engineer with professional experience in development, deployment and maintenance of features and enhancements in diverse software products. I have worked as a developer in the UI Centre of Excellence at Zycus where I contributed to the core libraries, products, and platforms. I have a passion for programming, a knack for problem solving and an aptitude for learning.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- HTML / CSS / JS
- C / Java
- Python
- SOL
- NodeJS / NPM

- Angular
- React
- Bootstrap / Sass
- MongoDB
- Spring

- **AWS Services**
- **REST Services**
- CI / CD Tools Git / BitBucket

# **WCAG**

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Zycus Infotech Pvt Ltd**

Mumbai, India

Associate Software Engineer

January 2021 - August 2022

- Led collaborative effort with stakeholders on 80+ complex business requirements over 20+ products, services, and applications
- Developed and enhanced 47+ front-end components for the UI component library and carried out Proof of Concept
- Implemented 3 observability visualization dashboards get comprehensive and granular visibility of products and services
- Liaised with UI/UX design teams and design leadership as Dev SPOC to audit adherence of products to WCAG standards Implemented the UI theme, 6 launch points and 10 manifestation areas for the app store platform and its integration in products
- Automated icon generation saving 12 hours per sprint and improved code reliability, maintainability, scalability, and security
- Groomed 8 resources through support channels, knowledge transfer sessions and authored documentation on best practices

#### OTHER PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Georgia State University, Computer Information Systems Department

Atlanta, GA

Graduate Assistant

August 2022 onwards

Developed professor's portfolio website and researched on advances in digital business transformation and process automation

#### **AVPS Technologies Inc**

Alpharetta, GA

Software Engineer Co-op

May 2023 - September 2023

- Mentored and guided junior developers, offering assistance and sharing knowledge to enhance overall performance of the team
- Refactored legacy code base ensuring adherence to software development standards improving performance and processes
- Implemented front-end components, microservices, back-end databases schemas, data visualization dashboards and unit tests

## INTERNSHIP & VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE

Android App & Game Development Instructor, CampK12

April 2020 - May 2020

Front-end Developer Intern, Fube Technology

December 2018 - March 2019

Android & Python Application Developer Intern, Trivia Softwares

June 2018 - July 2018

February 2018 - July 2018

- WordPress Administrator & SEO Manager Intern, Toppr
- General Secretary, Indian Society for Technical Education, SAKEC Chapter
- Math & Science Instructor Volunteer, Teach For India, Teach To Lead Foundation
- Founding Member, TAPtheTECH, NGO, YouTube Channel & Coursera Learning Hub
- Guest Speaker, Tech Routes Webinar, Computer Society of India, KJSCE Chapter

## **EDUCATION**

University of Mumbai

## Georgia State University, J. Mack Robinson College of Business

Atlanta, GA

Master of Science, Computer Information Systems, Digital Innovation, GPA - 4.0

August 2023

Certifications: Scrum Alliance - Certified Scrum Product Owner ®

Mumbai, India

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Engineering, GPA - 3.0

October 2020

#### SELECTED ACADEMIC PROJECTS

BHMS - Comprehensive IoT platform for monitoring structural health of bridges with Sensors and Image & Audio Processing Social Media Platform - Angular web application displaying profiles of fictional users with their details, posts, and image gallery Scribble Cloud - iOS automation script triggered using NFC to capture image of LCD writing pad and email it to user

**SpInput** - Prototype of a tertiary input device to augment keyboard and mouse that uses rotating a spinner wheel and clicking A11y Token - Proposal of an NFT Token and Marketplace platform for trading copyrights of UI/UX mockups and wireframes

## **PUBLICATION**

<sup>&#</sup>x27;Survey on IoT based Bridge Health Monitoring Systems', IJRESM, ISSN-2581-5792, Impact Factor- 5.72, April 2020